# **Julio Cesar Mauro**

• E-mail: juliomauro@gmail.com

• Linkeln: https://linkedin.com/in/juliomauro

• GitHUB: https://github.com/juliomauro

## **PROFESSIONAL SKILLS:**

As a seasoned professional with more than twenty years of experience, I had the opportunity of working for different industries such as Internet Service Providers, Banks, News Media and Tourism.

I have a broad experience in operations, systems architecture and infrastructure.

Between my knowledge of open source solutions and past experiences, I am able to deliver reliable and fast low-cost solutions.

My experience managing large and complex environments allows me to identify the best practices to deliver excellent results, both independently and as part of a team.

# **COMPUTER LITERACY:**

- Solid technological experience on several applications as follows: VMWare, Linux, AWS virtualization, PV2, Vmotion, Storage, HA, balancer, Tunning and vSphere and its functionalities.
- On AWS environment: Large experience on EC2, EBS, Security Group, VPC, VPN, AutoScaling,
  - Route 53, CloudWatch ELB, S3, CDN and RDS.
- On Linux environment: Solid experience with Web Servers, Varnish cache application, Wordpress
  - Blog server, VPN, FTP server, OpenLdap implementation, IPTables security FW, MySQL database,
  - AWStats, DHCP server, Linux Shell script coding, Phyton, Ansible, Terraform and also K8s for
  - computer tasks automation.
- On AWS platform: Vast experience on deploying new server machines and DR environment.
  - Administration of applications as follows: Balancers, Firewall, Backup, Storage and other
  - solutions such as AKAMAI CDN configuration and testing, BIG-IP, F5 and A10 Networks balancer
  - solutions. Irules, Virtual pool servers for servers loading distribution, Storage and iSCSI protocol.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

CVC Corp, Santo André / Trend Operadora, São Paulo

- DevOps on AWS and VMWare environments
- Cloud and infrastructure coordinator

- Responsible **for** supervising **the** staff infrastructure **and** internal support teams caring

for the good functioning of the Company's internal and external systems.

- Responsible **for the** AWS environment system (EC2, EBS, Security Group, VPC, VPN,

Auto Scaling, Route 53, Cloud Watch ELB, S3, CDN e RDS), **as** well **as for the** others

infrastructure segments **as** follows: Backup, linux implementations **and** VMware.

- Gained experience **on** implementing: ERP based **on** JDE Weblogic Oracle; NoSQL Mongo Data Base.
- Technical responsible **for the** following projects: Segue Viagem website **for** business traveling,

IT infrastructure migration **between** sites, Enterprise backup **and** restore **over the** AWS Amazon Cloud.

- Senior **on** DevOPS **for** optimization **and** automation **for** AWS, VMware **and** GCP making use **of** Git,

Docker, Ansilble and Terraform on Linux as on Windows platforms.

Good technical expertise on Rancher for containers management and FreeIPA.

#### Folha de S.Paulo, São Paulo

IT coordinator

# **JANUARY 2013 - OCTOBER 2015**

## Senior IT coordinator

• Responsible for supervising the staff's Linux and Data Base infrastructure teams caring for a good functioning of the Company's internal and external systems.

- **As** a coordenator, the main tasks were **as** follows: Reformulations **and** improvements **of** the web

systems, server process **and** newspaper printing solution; migration **of** XEN-Virtualization

platform to VMWare / Vsphere.

- Reponsible **for** implementing the VMware high ability virtualization pool **as** well **as for** 

redesigning the new Company's main Website, smartphone and tablet APP. e.g. Livraria da Folha,

Transfolha, Folhapress, **and** yet Backup **and** restore **new** infrastructure solution. Also, a **new** 

search engine based on Sphix and Elastic search was also implemented.

- Setup, improvement **and** thus management **of** the following systems: Digital TV indexing system

for means of collection purposes; MySQL Clustering; The Brazilian 2014
Elections IT infrastructure

environment; IT infrastructure **for** the 2014 World Cup **and not** less improvements **on** the

Company's Help Desk monitoring platform.

#### S.A. O Estado de S.Paulo, São Paulo

• VMWare and Linux Senior Consultant.

#### **MARCH 2009 - DECEMBER 2012**

- As a senior IT Consultant the main tasks were as follows: Responsible for maintaining and drawing
  - decisions about the Company's main news website and its infrastructure of servers over the VMware
  - virtualized environment, for purposes of ITIL best practices on maintenance, improvements and
  - upgrades. The achieved result was to deliver a high ability enterprise environment, cost reduction, fast infrastructure service deliver, fast new machines deploys and an efficient
  - administration over the all IT infrastructure environment.
- Head of the NIRVANA PROJECT. (Centralized Multi Platform Host Consolidation Project over VMWare 5.0).

# Technical manager for the following Company's IT projects:

- Estadão Home Website: Layout Upgrade and IT Infrastructure improvements.
- Estadão ESPN Broadcast Radio: Infrastructure implementation **for the** home website
- Estadão ESPN. Moving **of its** server machines **from** physical **to** virtual hosts.
- Mobile project: Woodwing server implementation **for** content deliver across mobile platform e.g.

Apple iPAD, SAMSUNG.

- Estadão Collection Deliver project: For deliver **of** 137 years **of** Company's news paper collection

over the web.

- HP iSCSI 4000 Series Storage Hardware - AKAMAI CDN - Varnish Cache **for** fast Apache HTTP

front-end content deliver and Real Media OAS 11 advertising banner deliver.

Other project learship were **as** follows:

- Divirta-se, E+, PME, Piauí, Economia, Política **and** Wordpress blogs.

## Sterling Commerce, São Paulo e Curitiba

Senior Linux and GIS Consultant

# **MARCH 2007 - JANUARY 2009**

- As a Linux and Gentran Integration Suite consultant for some of the knownest Bank Companies in Brazil, the main tasks were as follow:
- Data file seek exchange
- Data processing
- process management
- Senior Linux/Unix professional consulting.
  - Manager of the following projects:

- File transfer **for** HSBC Bank **in** order **to** unify the payment **system** between the Brazilian branches.
- Itaú Bank international payment system project launched.
- Itaú Bank international payment **system** integration **for** the national branches.
- Itaú Bank and Bank of Brazil payment system integration project.
- Instructor **for** the GIS Gentran Integration Suite **for** new clients **and** consultants over Linux, Unix
  - and Solaris operational systems platforms.

# **EDUCATION**

Kaplan International English, Toronto, Canadá

**NOVEMBER 2017 - DECEMBER 2017** 

• Intensive English to improve quickly on English fluency and learn grammar and vocabulary.

FASP, São Paulo

FEBRUARY 2002 - NOVEMBER 2007

• Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering

FECAP, São Paulo

FEBRUARY 1995 - DECEMBER 1997

• Data Processing Technician

PROFESSIONAL ON JOB COMPUTER AND CERTIFIED TRAINING COURSES:

- AWS Security Fundamentals
- AWS Certified SysOps Administrator
- AWS EC2: High availability and scalable
- AWS Technical Essentials
- AWS Technical Professional
- AWS Solutions Architect
- AWS CloudFront
- AWS EC2, CloudFront **and** the Route53 Alura
- AWS S3: Object working out and storage on Cloud Alura
- Docker
- Git: Computer Code controlling and sharing
- VMWare NSX: The technical overview
- VMware Certified Professional
- VMware VCenter: Configuration Manager
- VMware Virtual SAN: Deploy and Manage [V5.5]
- VMware vSphere with Operations Management
- VMware vSphere: Data protection and recover fundamentals
- VMware vSphere: Fast Track [V5.5]
- VMware vSphere: Setup, Configure and Management
- VMware vSphere: Optimizing and Scaling
- Docker: Setup **and** management Alura
- Sophos Endpoint Cerfitied
- Cisco Executive Workshop Attendee
- Clusters **and** high ability on Linux Sucesu SP
- ITIL Foundation V3
- JIRA Administration
- Linux Professional Institute LPI 101 e 102

# **LANGUAGE SKILLS:**

- Brazilian Portuguese as the native language.
- Advanced English as the secondary language.
- Advanced Italian as the Italian citizenship language.

### OTHER INFORMATION WHICH MAY CONCERN:

- US Valid VISA.
- European Citizenship.